{"questions": [
    {
      "question": "If (5.55)^x = (0.555)^y = 1000, then the value of 1/x - 1/y is",
      "options": ["1", "1/3", "2/3", "3"],
      "answer": "1/3"
    },
    {
      "question": "A club has 256 members of whom 144 can play football, 123 can play tennis, and 132 can play cricket. Moreover, 58 members can play both football and tennis, 25 can play both cricket and tennis, while 63 can play both football and cricket. If every member can play at least one game, then the number of members who can play only tennis is",
      "options": ["32", "43", "38", "45"],
      "answer": "43"
    },
    {
      "question": "In a circle of radius 11 cm, CD is a diameter and AB is a chord of length 20.5 cm. If AB and CD intersect at a point E inside the circle and CE has length 7 cm, then the difference of the lengths of BE and AE, in cm, is",
      "options": ["1.5", "3.5", "0.5", "2.5"],
      "answer": "0.5"
    },
    {
      "question": "Meena scores 40% in an examination and after review, even though her score is increased by 50%, she fails by 35 marks. If her post-review score is increased by 20%, she will have 7 marks more than the passing score. The percentage score needed for passing the examination is",
      "options": ["75", "80", "60", "70"],
      "answer": "70"
    },
    {
      "question": "Corners are cut off from an equilateral triangle T to produce a regular hexagon H. Then, the ratio of the area of H to the area of T is",
      "options": ["5:6", "3:4", "2:3", "4:5"],
      "answer": "2:3"
    },
    {
      "question": "If the population of a town is p in the beginning of any year then it becomes 3+2p in the beginning of the next year. If the population in the beginning of 2019 is 1000, then the population in the beginning of 2034 will be",
      "options": ["(1003)^15 + 6", "(977)^15 - 3", "(1003)^215 - 3", "(977)^214 + 3"],
      "answer": "(1003)^215 - 3"
    },
    {
      "question": "The product of two positive numbers is 616. If the ratio of the difference of their cubes to the cube of their difference is 157:3, then the sum of the two numbers is",
      "options": ["50", "85", "95", "58"],
      "answer": "50"
    },
    {
      "question": "On selling a pen at 5% loss and a book at 15% gain, Karim gains Rs. 7. If he sells the pen at 5% gain and the book at 10% gain, he gains Rs. 13. What is the cost price of the book in Rupees?",
      "options": ["80", "85", "100", "95"],
      "answer": "80"
    },
    {
      "question": "Two cars travel the same distance starting at 10:00 am and 11:00 am, respectively, on the same day. They reach their common destination at the same point of time. If the first car travelled for at least 6 hours, then the highest possible value of the percentage by which the speed of the second car could exceed that of the first car is",
      "options": ["20", "10", "35", "25"],
      "answer": "20"
    },
    {
      "question": "At their usual efficiency levels, A and B together finish a task in 12 days. If A had worked half as efficiently as she usually does, and B had worked thrice as efficiently as he usually does, the task would have been completed in 9 days. How many days would A take to finish the task if she works alone at her usual efficiency?",
      "options": ["18", "12", "24", "36"],
      "answer": "18"
    },
    {
      "question": "The number of the real roots of the equation 2cos(x(x + 1)) = 2x + 2^-x is",
      "options": ["0", "Infinite", "1", "2"],
      "answer": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "The income of Amala is 20% more than that of Bimala and 20% less than that of Kamala. If Kamala's income goes down by 4% and Bimala's goes up by 10%, then the percentage by which Kamala's income would exceed Bimala's is nearest to",
      "options": ["28", "29", "31", "32"],
      "answer": "31"
    },
    {
      "question": "If a1, a2, ......... are in A.P, then 1/√a1 + √a2 + 1/√a2 + √a3 + ...... + 1/√an + √a(n+1) equals",
      "options": ["n/√an + √a(n+1)", "n-1/√a1 + √an", "n/√a1 - √a(n+1)", "n-1/√a1 - √an"],
      "answer": "n/√an + √a(n+1)"
    },
    {
      "question": "AB is a diameter of a circle of radius 5 cm. Let P and Q be two points on the circle so that the length of PB is 6 cm, and the length of AP is twice that of AQ. Then the length, in cm, of QB is nearest to",
      "options": ["8.5", "9.3", "9.1", "7.8"],
      "answer": "9.1"
    },
    {
      "question": "One can use three different transports which move at 10, 20, and 30 kmph, respectively. To reach from A to B, Amal took each mode of transport 1/3 of his total journey time, while Bimal took each mode of transport 1/3 of the total distance. The percentage by which Bimal's travel time exceeds Amal's travel time is nearest to",
      "options": ["22", "19", "21", "20"],
      "answer": "22"
    },
    {
        "question": "Amala, Bina, and Gouri invest money in the ratio 3 : 4 : 5 in fixed deposits having respective annual interest rates in the ratio 6 : 5 : 4. What is their total interest income (in Rs) after a year, if Bina's interest income exceeds Amala's by Rs 250?",
        "options": ["7000", "6000", "6350", "7250"],
        "answer": "7250"
      },
      {
        "question": "If m and n are integers such that (√2)^19 * 34 * 42 * 9m * 8n = 3n * 16m * (∜64), then m is",
        "options": ["-16", "-24", "-12", "-20"],
        "answer": "-12"
      },
      {
        "question": "A chemist mixes two liquids 1 and 2. One litre of liquid 1 weighs 1 kg and one litre of liquid 2 weighs 800 gm. If half litre of the mixture weighs 480 gm, then the percentage of liquid 1 in the mixture, in terms of volume, is",
        "options": ["70", "85", "80", "75"],
        "answer": "80"
      },
      {
        "question": "Let x and y be positive real numbers such that log5(x + y) + log5(x - y) = 3, and log2y - log2x = 1 - log23. Then xy equals",
        "options": ["25", "150", "250", "100"],
        "answer": "150"
      },
      {
        "question": "If the rectangular faces of a brick have their diagonals in the ratio 3 : 2√3 : √15, then the ratio of the length of the shortest edge of the brick to that of its longest edge is",
        "options": ["1:√3", "2:√5", "√2:√3", "√3:2"],
        "answer": "1:√3"
      },
      {
        "question": "The product of the distinct roots of |x^2 - x - 6| = x + 2 is",
        "options": ["-4", "-16", "-8", "-24"],
        "answer": "-16"
      },
      {
        "question": "The wheels of bicycles A and B have radii 30 cm and 40 cm, respectively. While traveling a certain distance, each wheel of A required 5000 more revolutions than each wheel of B. If bicycle B traveled this distance in 45 minutes, then its speed, in km per hour, was",
        "options": ["18π", "16π", "12π", "14π"],
        "answer": "16π"
      },
      {
        "question": "Ramesh and Gautam are among 22 students who write an examination. Ramesh scores 82.5. The average score of the 21 students other than Gautam is 62. The average score of all the 22 students is one more than the average score of the 21 students other than Ramesh. The score of Gautam is",
        "options": ["51", "53", "49", "48"],
        "answer": "51"
      },
      {
        "question": "The real root of the equation 26x + 23x+2 - 21 = 0 is",
        "options": ["log23/3", "log29", "log27/3", "log227"],
        "answer": "log23/3"
      },
      {
        "question": "The average of 30 integers is 5. Among these 30 integers, there are exactly 20 which do not exceed 5. What is the highest possible value of the average of these 20 integers?",
        "options": ["4", "5", "4.5", "3.5"],
        "answer": "4.5"
      },
      {
        "question": "Let a, b, x, y be real numbers such that a^2 + b^2 = 25, x^2 + y^2 = 169 and ax + by = 65. If k = ay - bx, then?",
        "options": ["k = 0", "k > 5/13", "k = 5/13", "0 < k <= 5/13"],
        "answer": "k = 0"
      },
      {
        "question": "In a triangle ABC, medians AD and BE are perpendicular to each other, and have lengths 12 cm and 9 cm, respectively. Then, the area of triangle ABC, in sq cm, is?",
        "options": ["80", "68", "72", "78"],
        "answer": "72"
      },
      {
        "question": "Let a1, a2 be integers such that a1 - a2 + a3 - a4 + (-1)^(n-1) an = n, for n ≥ 1. Then a51 + a52 + …. + a1023 equals?",
        "options": ["-1", "1", "0", "10"],
        "answer": "1"
      },
      {
        "question": "Two circles, each of radius 4 cm, touch externally. Each of these two circles is touched externally by a third circle. If these three circles have a common tangent, then the radius of the third circle, in cm, is?",
        "options": ["π/3", "1", "1/√2", "√2"],
        "answer": "1"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the largest positive integer such that (n² + 7n + 12) / (n² - n - 12) is also a positive integer?",
        "options": ["6", "8", "16", "12"],
        "answer": "12"
      },
      {
        "question": "In 2010, a library contained a total of 11500 books in two categories - fiction and non-fiction. In 2015, the library contained a total of 12760 books in these two categories. During this period, there was a 10% increase in the fiction category while there was a 12% increase in the non-fiction category. How many fiction books were in the library in 2015?",
        "options": ["6600", "6160", "6000", "5500"],
        "answer": "6600"
      },
      {
        "question": "A cyclist leaves A at 10 am and reaches B at 11 am. Starting from 10:01 am, every minute a motorcycle leaves A and moves towards B. Forty-five such motorcycles reach B by 11 am. All motorcycles have the same speed. If the cyclist had doubled his speed, how many motorcycles would have reached B by the time the cyclist reached B?",
        "options": ["22", "20", "15", "23"],
        "answer": "15"
      },
      {
        "question": "The real root of the equation 26x + 23x+2 - 21 = 0 is",
        "options": ["log23/3", "log29", "log27/3", "log227"],
        "answer": "log23/3"
      },
      {
        "question": "The average of 30 integers is 5. Among these 30 integers, there are exactly 20 which do not exceed 5. What is the highest possible value of the average of these 20 integers?",
        "options": ["4", "5", "4.5", "3.5"],
        "answer": "4.5"
      },
      {
        "question": "Let a, b, x, y be real numbers such that a^2 + b^2 = 25, x^2 + y^2 = 169 and ax + by = 65. If k = ay - bx, then?",
        "options": ["k = 0", "k > 5/13", "k = 5/13", "0 < k <= 5/13"],
        "answer": "k = 0"
      },
      {
        "question": "In a triangle ABC, medians AD and BE are perpendicular to each other, and have lengths 12 cm and 9 cm, respectively. Then, the area of triangle ABC, in sq cm, is?",
        "options": ["80", "68", "72", "78"],
        "answer": "72"
      },
      {
        "question": "Let a1, a2 be integers such that a1 - a2 + a3 - a4 + (-1)^(n-1) an = n, for n ≥ 1. Then a51 + a52 + …. + a1023 equals?",
        "options": ["-1", "1", "0", "10"],
        "answer": "1"
      },
      {
        "question": "Two circles, each of radius 4 cm, touch externally. Each of these two circles is touched externally by a third circle. If these three circles have a common tangent, then the radius of the third circle, in cm, is?",
        "options": ["π/3", "1", "1/√2", "√2"],
        "answer": "1"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the largest positive integer such that (n² + 7n + 12) / (n² - n - 12) is also a positive integer?",
        "options": ["6", "8", "16", "12"],
        "answer": "12"
      },
      {
        "question": "In 2010, a library contained a total of 11500 books in two categories - fiction and non-fiction. In 2015, the library contained a total of 12760 books in these two categories. During this period, there was a 10% increase in the fiction category while there was a 12% increase in the non-fiction category. How many fiction books were in the library in 2015?",
        "options": ["6600", "6160", "6000", "5500"],
        "answer": "6600"
      },
      {
        "question": "A cyclist leaves A at 10 am and reaches B at 11 am. Starting from 10:01 am, every minute a motorcycle leaves A and moves towards B. Forty-five such motorcycles reach B by 11 am. All motorcycles have the same speed. If the cyclist had doubled his speed, how many motorcycles would have reached B by the time the cyclist reached B?",
        "options": ["22", "20", "15", "23"],
        "answer": "15"
      },
      {
        "question": "The real root of the equation 26x + 23x+2 - 21 = 0 is",
        "options": ["log23/3", "log29", "log27/3", "log227"],
        "answer": "log23/3"
      },
      {
        "question": "The average of 30 integers is 5. Among these 30 integers, there are exactly 20 which do not exceed 5. What is the highest possible value of the average of these 20 integers?",
        "options": ["4", "5", "4.5", "3.5"],
        "answer": "4.5"
      },
      {
        "question": "Let a, b, x, y be real numbers such that a^2 + b^2 = 25, x^2 + y^2 = 169 and ax + by = 65. If k = ay - bx, then?",
        "options": ["k = 0", "k > 5/13", "k = 5/13", "0 < k <= 5/13"],
        "answer": "k = 0"
      },
      {
        "question": "In a triangle ABC, medians AD and BE are perpendicular to each other, and have lengths 12 cm and 9 cm, respectively. Then, the area of triangle ABC, in sq cm, is?",
        "options": ["80", "68", "72", "78"],
        "answer": "72"
      },
      {
        "question": "Let a1, a2 be integers such that a1 - a2 + a3 - a4 + (-1)^(n-1) an = n, for n ≥ 1. Then a51 + a52 + …. + a1023 equals?",
        "options": ["-1", "1", "0", "10"],
        "answer": "1"
      },
      {
        "question": "Two circles, each of radius 4 cm, touch externally. Each of these two circles is touched externally by a third circle. If these three circles have a common tangent, then the radius of the third circle, in cm, is?",
        "options": ["π/3", "1", "1/√2", "√2"],
        "answer": "1"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the largest positive integer such that (n² + 7n + 12) / (n² - n - 12) is also a positive integer?",
        "options": ["6", "8", "16", "12"],
        "answer": "12"
      },
      {
        "question": "In 2010, a library contained a total of 11500 books in two categories - fiction and non-fiction. In 2015, the library contained a total of 12760 books in these two categories. During this period, there was a 10% increase in the fiction category while there was a 12% increase in the non-fiction category. How many fiction books were in the library in 2015?",
        "options": ["6600", "6160", "6000", "5500"],
        "answer": "6600"
      },
      {
        "question": "A cyclist leaves A at 10 am and reaches B at 11 am. Starting from 10:01 am, every minute a motorcycle leaves A and moves towards B. Forty-five such motorcycles reach B by 11 am. All motorcycles have the same speed. If the cyclist had doubled his speed, how many motorcycles would have reached B by the time the cyclist reached B?",
        "options": ["22", "20", "15", "23"],
        "answer": "15"
      },
          {
            "question": "Let A be a real number. Then the roots of the equation x² - 4x - log₂A = 0 are real and distinct if and only if?",
            "options": ["A < 1/16", "A > 1/8", "A > 1/16", "A < 1/8"],
            "answer": "A > 1/16"
          },
          {
            "question": "Anil alone can do a job in 20 days while Sunil alone can do it in 40 days. Anil starts the job, and after 3 days, Sunil joins him. Again, after a few more days, Bimal joins them and they together finish the job. If Bimal has done 10% of the job, then in how many days was the job done?",
            "options": ["13", "12", "15", "14"],
            "answer": "13"
          },
          {
            "question": "In an examination, Rama's score was one-twelfth of the sum of the scores of Mohan and Anjali. After a review, the score of each of them increased by 6. The revised scores of Anjali, Mohan, and Rama were in the ratio 11:10:3. Then Anjali's score exceeded Rama's score by?",
            "options": ["26", "32", "24", "35"],
            "answer": "32"
          },
          {
            "question": "The base of a regular pyramid is a square and each of the other four sides is an equilateral triangle, length of each side being 20 cm. The vertical height of the pyramid, in cm, is?",
            "options": ["10√2", "8√3", "12", "5√5"],
            "answer": "10√2"
          },
          {
            "question": "If x is a real number, then √loge(4x-x²) is a real number if and only if?",
            "options": ["-3≤x≤3", "1≤x≤2", "1≤x≤3", "-1≤x≤3"],
            "answer": "1≤x≤3"
          },
          {
            "question": "Let ABC be a right-angled triangle with hypotenuse BC of length 20 cm. If AP is perpendicular on BC, then the maximum possible length of AP, in cm, is?",
            "options": ["10", "8√2", "6√3", "5"],
            "answer": "10"
          },
          {
            "question": "Two ants A and B start from a point P on a circle at the same time, with A moving clock-wise and B moving anti-clockwise. They meet for the first time at 10:00 am when A has covered 60% of the track. If A returns to P at 10:12 am, then B returns to P at?",
            "options": ["10:27 am", "10:25 am", "10:45 am", "10:18 am"],
            "answer": "10:27 am"
          },
          {
            "question": "The salaries of Ramesh, Ganesh, and Rajesh were in the ratio 6:5:7 in 2010, and in the ratio 3:4:3 in 2015. If Ramesh's salary increased by 25% during 2010-2015, then the percentage increase in Rajesh's salary during this period is closest to?",
            "options": ["7", "8", "9", "10"],
            "answer": "7"
          },
          {
            "question": "A man makes complete use of 405 cc of iron, 783 cc of aluminium, and 351 cc of copper to make a number of solid right circular cylinders of each type of metal. These cylinders have the same volume and each of these has radius 3 cm. If the total number of cylinders is to be kept at a minimum, then the total surface area of all these cylinders, in sq cm, is?",
            "options": ["1044(4 + π)", "8464π", "928π", "1026(1 + π)"],
            "answer": "1026(1 + π)"
          },
          {
            "question": "The quadratic equation x² + bx + c = 0 has two roots 4a and 3a, where a is an integer. Which of the following is a possible value of b² + c?",
            "options": ["3721", "549", "361", "427"],
            "answer": "549"
          },
          {
            "question": "Mukesh purchased 10 bicycles in 2017, all at the same price. He sold six of these at a profit of 25% and the remaining four at a loss of 25%. If he made a total profit of Rs. 2000, then his purchase price of a bicycle, in Rupees, was?",
            "options": ["2000", "6000", "8000", "4000"],
            "answer": "4000"
          },
          {
            "question": "The number of common terms in the two sequences: 15, 19, 23, 27, ...... , 415 and 14, 19, 24, 29, ...... , 464 is?",
            "options": ["20", "18", "21", "19"],
            "answer": "20"
          },
          
              {
                "question": "A new game show on TV has 100 boxes numbered 1, 2, ....., 100 in a row, each containing a mystery prize. The prizes are items of different types, a, b, c, ....., in decreasing order of value. The most expensive item is of type a, a diamond ring, and there is exactly one of these. You are told that the number of items at least doubles as you move to the next type. For example, there would be at least twice as many items of type b as of type a, at least twice as many items of type c as of type b and so on. There is no particular order in which the prizes are placed in the boxes. Which of the following is not possible? There are exactly 30 items of type b. There are exactly 75 items of type e. There are exactly 60 items of type d. There are exactly 45 items of type c.Which of the following is not possible?",
                "options": ["There are exactly 30 items of type b.","There are exactly 75 items of type e." , "There are exactly 60 items of type d.","There are exactly 45 items of type c." ],
                "answer": "There are exactly 45 items of type c."
              },
              {
                 "question": "A new game show on TV has 100 boxes numbered 1, 2, ....., 100 in a row, each containing a mystery prize. The prizes are items of different types, a, b, c, ....., in decreasing order of value. The most expensive item is of type a, a diamond ring, and there is exactly one of these. You are told that the number of items at least doubles as you move to the next type. For example, there would be at least twice as many items of type b as of type a, at least twice as many items of type c as of type b and so on. There is no particular order in which the prizes are placed in the boxes. Which of the following is not possible? There are exactly 30 items of type b. There are exactly 75 items of type e. There are exactly 60 items of type d. There are exactly 45 items of type C.You ask for the type of item in box 45. Instead of being given a direct answer, you are told that there are 31 items of the same type as box 45 in boxes 1 to 44 and 43 items of the same type as box 45 in boxes 46 to 100. What is the maximum possible number of different types of items?",
                "options": [5, 6, 3, 4],
                "answer": "5"
              },
              
                  {
                    "question": "Princess, Queen, Rani and Samragni were the four finalists in a dance competition. Ashman, Badal, Gagan and Dyu were the four music composers who individually assigned items to the dancers. Each dancer had to individually perform in two dance items assigned by the different composers. The first items performed by the four dancers were all assigned by different music composers. No dancer performed her second item before the performance of the first item by any other dancers. The dancers performed their second items in the same sequence of their performance of their first items. The following additional facts are known. i) No composer who assigned item to Princess, assigned any item to Queen. ii) No composer who assigned item to Rani, assigned any item to Samragni. iii) The first performance was by Princess; this item was assigned by Badal. iv) The last performance was by Rani; this item was assigned by Gagan. v) The items assigned by Ashman were performed consecutively. The number of performances between items assigned by each of the remaining composers was the same. Which of the following is true?",
                    "options": [
                      "The third performance was composed by Ashman.",
                      "The second performance was composed by Dyu.",
                      "The second performance was composed by Gagan.",
                      "The third performance was composed by Dyu."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The third performance was composed by Dyu."
                  },
                  {
                    "question": "Princess, Queen, Rani and Samragni were the four finalists in a dance competition. Ashman, Badal, Gagan and Dyu were the four music composers who individually assigned items to the dancers. Each dancer had to individually perform in two dance items assigned by the different composers. The first items performed by the four dancers were all assigned by different music composers. No dancer performed her second item before the performance of the first item by any other dancers. The dancers performed their second items in the same sequence of their performance of their first items. The following additional facts are known. i) No composer who assigned item to Princess, assigned any item to Queen. ii) No composer who assigned item to Rani, assigned any item to Samragni. iii) The first performance was by Princess; this item was assigned by Badal. iv) The last performance was by Rani; this item was assigned by Gagan. v) The items assigned by Ashman were performed consecutively. The number of performances between items assigned by each of the remaining composers was the same. Which of the following is FALSE?",
                    "options": [
                      "Queen did not perform in any item composed by Gagan.",
                      "Rani did not perform in any item composed by Badal.",
                      "Samragni did not perform in any item composed by Ashman.",
                      "Princess did not perform in any item composed by Dyu."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Queen did not perform in any item composed by Gagan."
                  },
                  {
                    "question": "Princess, Queen, Rani and Samragni were the four finalists in a dance competition. Ashman, Badal, Gagan and Dyu were the four music composers who individually assigned items to the dancers. Each dancer had to individually perform in two dance items assigned by the different composers. The first items performed by the four dancers were all assigned by different music composers. No dancer performed her second item before the performance of the first item by any other dancers. The dancers performed their second items in the same sequence of their performance of their first items. The following additional facts are known. i) No composer who assigned item to Princess, assigned any item to Queen. ii) No composer who assigned item to Rani, assigned any item to Samragni. iii) The first performance was by Princess; this item was assigned by Badal. iv) The last performance was by Rani; this item was assigned by Gagan. v) The items assigned by Ashman were performed consecutively. The number of performances between items assigned by each of the remaining composers was the same. The sixth performance was composed by:",
                    "options": [
                      "Gagan",
                      "Ashman",
                      "Badal",
                      "Dyu"
                    ],
                    "answer": "Badal"
                  },
                  {
                    "question": "Princess, Queen, Rani and Samragni were the four finalists in a dance competition. Ashman, Badal, Gagan and Dyu were the four music composers who individually assigned items to the dancers. Each dancer had to individually perform in two dance items assigned by the different composers. The first items performed by the four dancers were all assigned by different music composers. No dancer performed her second item before the performance of the first item by any other dancers. The dancers performed their second items in the same sequence of their performance of their first items. The following additional facts are known. i) No composer who assigned item to Princess, assigned any item to Queen. ii) No composer who assigned item to Rani, assigned any item to Samragni. iii) The first performance was by Princess; this item was assigned by Badal. iv) The last performance was by Rani; this item was assigned by Gagan. v) The items assigned by Ashman were performed consecutively. The number of performances between items assigned by each of the remaining composers was the same. Which pair of performances were composed by the same composer?",
                    "options": [
                      "The third and the seventh",
                      "The first and the seventh",
                      "The first and the sixth",
                      "The second and the sixth"
                    ],
                    "answer": "The first and the seventh"
                  }
                ]
              }
              
            
        
        
    
  
      
    
